Welcome back to
class, and we're going to do a little more
lamb. Here we go, we
're
in... Okay, very
good, it's completely empty. Okay, very
good. We're
looking at the perfection of
giving, and
we saw... we're going to finish in
koto, and it was four years of
work. They're
talking about the kinds of ways we
can give,
kinds of ways of giving that aren't good.
For example, you can't give alcohol to
a calf and things like that. Here's an
example: "ch" means cow.
Here, "chuin" is the old word for
sacrifice, and it was a tradition to sacrifice
a cow in the fire. So this kind
of giving
is a bad idea, a wrong idea. And
there are many stories about people who
make cow offerings and end up
being the next
cow. And here's a list of bad
attitudes when you're giving, when you're being
virtuous. Your mind also has to be
in a good
place. So if you're going to... even if you're going to
give some money to the
Way project, for
example, you have to avoid
certain thought patterns that make
that way of giving a little
weird. You give, but you're kind of annoyed
about giving. That's the first one.
I'm going to give a little bit more than that other
country. Our stupa is going to be a little bit
bigger.  Okay, this is being competitive,
it's giving
competitively. The third one is, I hope
everyone finds out that I was the one who gave the
most money and that everyone is
impressed
with me. And it means
in Sanskrit, and it's famous, and it's like, I
hope everyone hears what an
amazing person I am to give.
Yumba means like a little depressed,
so it says you should be in a
good mood, you should be
happy, you should be
content, you shouldn't be like, "Ah, I hope you're done with
these ways of raising money."
Now, with the
class,
hon is very, very, very important. Hon
means tuna. He was talking to me and he
excited everyone, he made all the
countries compete with each other. I got
excited, I offered too much money, and
now I'm a little stuck. Now I have to give it back.
So it means I got excited and I saw too much.
And of course, it happens when you're in
this business of giving. Sometimes you get
too excited and you promise, you promise too much,
and you say, "I'm going to build the
cabin," and then you say, "Oh my God, what was I
thinking?" So it's very
important that you don't have regrets,
just shut up and  Give it and
no in English we say like no don't hesitate no just
keep quiet Do it be happy and
next time
Control yourself
Okay okay
ch means I'm going to help my
friends but I'm not going to help other
people then chog
means yes that something is like not in its
proper place you help the people you like
and you don't help those you do
n't My country for example every 10 years
decides they want to hate another world And
when you're 71 you realize
these things and the enemy changes every 10
[Music]
years they go to different countries Ah no now
they're the bad guys Ah I already dealt with them
with bad people No they're good
but this year they're the bad guys and this
is my country's enemy And the next
year it changes again And when you're 71
you realize it changes every 5
years So every time people in
my country say that Ah these people
the Arabs are bad the Germans are
bad the Russians are bad other people
are bad Every time I hear this I try
to go to that
country So I went to
Morocco I did a two-month retreat  And
I was
with the
imam, and they were from the Taliban, and they
were the enemies of the United States, and we
were all friends, and everyone was very
kind, and we had a very
nice time. There's a joke in the
monastery that says, "I
forget more things than you're
going to
learn, like how the enemy changes all the
time, don't believe it, forget it, be
friends with
everyone, and everyone is the same, and everyone wants to
be friends with you, just be a friend to everyone." And it's
very nice, and it's very nice to be able to
say, "I'm friends with everyone, I
love all
countries." When I lived in New
York and was visiting these
Muslim countries, there were bombs and stuff, and they would ask me
where I was from, and I would tell them I was
from
Manhattan, and they would ask me, "What's Manhattan?" And I said, "It's
an island that's far from the
United States."
So, look, everyone is fine,
everyone is a good person. When you travel a
lot,
you discover that people are kind everywhere,
and if you are kind to
them,
with marapa means, "Don't let
your act of giving be
contaminated." The next
image, when I heard this, I said, "Oh
my God, this is so funny, people!"
Then they try to keep them
white, and I thought, "This is crazy to me, it's crazy." They
buy white sneakers and
then spray them to keep them
white. I don't even have time to
find new shoes, and they have
the time to spray them.
This is an interesting idea.
As the section on the
perfection of
giving comes to a close, it has a very beautiful section, and I think it would be
a great complete teaching
to give here at Mountain. And it's
quoting Shanti Deva's other famous book
that nobody knows. Shanti Deva
wrote two
incredible books. So we know
The Guide to the Divine,
but she wrote another book
called The Divine Sutras, which collected all the best
advice from the
ancient sutras, and I've always wanted to
teach it because I said, "If The Guide to the Divine Sutras
is so
incredible, this book must be like a
secret rock and roll hit." So I've
worked on
this one,
and I hate to say this, I shouldn't say this,
but I feel like it's not
as good. It's because he's not
writing; he just collected
quotes from other places, and it's not like his
other
book. His other book is one of the
best books ever written,
but this other book is just like
a big collection of quotes, and it's very
long, so I decided not to work on it.
But here he does a
You have to know
that this is very beautiful and it says
all the things you have
now: your body, all your possessions, and
your
time. Once you become a
Bapa, you've already sold all of this:
your
body, your white shoes, your house, your
money, your time. For M, it's the most
precious thing there is.
Everything that
belongs to you, or that is yours, like a Bodis, you
already promised to give it away. So it's
no longer
yours. You're just taking care of
these things until you finish this act
of giving. Everything that is yours, everything that
belongs to you, you've already dedicated to other
people. And your time and your body, you've already
offered them to be the servant of all
beings. Therefore, they no longer belong to you. You're
just taking care of them,
temporarily holding onto them
until the date you have to
hand them over. You are the warehouse of Amazon. These
things aren't
yours; you are the warehouse. It's just that they haven't been
delivered yet: your body, your
money, your time, like a Bodis. When
you took your
Bodis vows, you already committed to giving these things to
other people. You're just
keeping them until the time comes.
Give them up. Now I want your money, now
I want your house, now I want...
and it
says while these things are still
in the vault, you have the responsibility
to take very good care of them. They are no longer
yours. Once you take your vows,
all your money, all your things, all your
time, and your
body, you have already given them up. You
simply don't take it up;
you are only taking care of it. It is
no longer yours; it belongs to other people.
You have to stay healthy; it is
your responsibility to stay
healthy because it is no longer your body. I
think it's a very beautiful idea. If
you say, "My wife says that my... my belly
button,
my shirt opens
here," some people like John, "His
shirt opens up here, up here, down here,"
and my wife
says, "Hey, your
shirt... Then you can't gain weight
because it will make you
sick. You can't gain weight;
you have to go to the gym; you have to
do your yoga; you have to eat
healthy because it is no longer your body; it
no longer
belongs to you. You are temporarily taking care of it;
you are the temporary caretaker of these things. You have them
stored in the vault until
the date you have to give them up." And
I think it's a beautiful argument.
And that's how the first
perfection ends. He quotes Shantideva and says, "No."
You have the right to be overweight, you don't
have the right to not sleep, you don't have
the right to not take care of yourself. That
body doesn't belong to you. You already promised you'd
give it up, which means you should
join the Goodnight Club.
If
you want to bother the tech team,
keep asking for things you didn't ask for
before. Well, they'll sort it out.
I feel like this
Goodnight Group is one of the best
ideas we've had. You promise to do it at
10 PM, and here I do it at 9
AM and 5 AM, but at my house I do it
at 10 PM, and Rob comes over and
takes my computer and my cell phone. And
honestly, it's something I look forward to. I wake up
and say, "Where's my
computer? Where's my
cell phone? I have to look up the
temperature,"
and then I say, "Maybe it's not
important." Does that ever happen to you? When
you join this club, you'll
discover strange
thoughts, like asking if nails
grow easily or
quickly. And these are things you
look up, but it's
called the Goodnight Group, and it's at
PM. If you live alone or something
like that, sometimes my wife has to go to
another house.  that she has to take care of and when
she's home
the cell phone is on the other side and then I
have to cross to the other side if I
want it and then it hits me. It's like that's not
important, what you want to look for and if it's not
there I give it to Rob. He picks it up at
10 at night. There's a joke, but ah, they
give you one of these
paper books and you
ask for Mix Man translations. One side at
10 at
night, open the Mix Man book. I swear you'll be
asleep in 2
minutes. It's so hard and so deep, it's
amazing to go to sleep. If you want
my favorite,
Esica puts me to sleep in two
seconds, so have a paper book,
put it next to your bed and at 10 at
night
leave your computer, put it somewhere you ca
n't reach it because you're going to
get to it, you're going to find a way to
get to it. If you're in a hotel
you need to add the TV remote too.
I don't have a hotel at my
house but when I'm traveling, ah, here it is,
please join.
It's the best I can teach you. I've been teaching
for 100 years,
I have 2.5 million files in  I
've taught my whole life about computers.
But this is the
best thing: you're going to sleep well, you're going to be happy, you're going
to be creative, you're not going to
think about bad things at night. I
never slept 8 hours in my whole life, and
now I sleep 8 hours like a baby, and by
10 I'm already up and about. By 6 in the morning
I'm up and about
and I can work. I start working at
6:05 and I
don't allow any appointments or meetings until
11, so I work for 5 hours and it's incredible, it's
incredible. You came here so I could
teach you something. This is the best thing I
can teach you. Join the group of
good people, we call it, in short, the
goodnight club, and the shorter abbreviation
is the Night
Club. But this is the best thing I can
give you. It's the best thing I can teach you. Don't
wait until you're 72, it's
silly. Do it
now and you're going to be much more productive, and your
mind is going to be clearer and
happier. Your meditation is going to be incredible.
Read a book when you go to sleep and
when you wake up, meditate.  In those 5 or
10 minutes, your life will
change
completely. If you came here to learn something,
this is what you have to join.
Here, the Dean's Council,
to take care of these things,
has TR or
CU. There are four parts in three groups, but you do
n't have to worry about the
number. You've already committed your body to
other people. Yes, you've already made your vows
somewhere. There you said, "I am
the servant of all beings."
That's the
vow: I promise to be a servant of other
beings. I give my body. So it's no longer yours.
Don't take your vows lightly. It's
a very
big commitment. Then all your things become the
property of all
beings. First of all, you must keep
reminding yourself that you've already
committed your things to other
people. You've already made this
commitment, and this is very
important. Even the right moment when you're going to
give
this up is your
responsibility. Take care of your body and don't
hurt it, don't allow it to be
hurt. Don't overdo it, don't
stop exercising, don't
stop doing your chores. Your place is not your body anymore; you've already
promised it to someone else.
Therefore, you have to take care of it. I don't know about you,
but I have problems.  Taking care of
myself for selfish reasons, you know, like, if
my wife tells me, "You have to take
care of yourself, you have to eat vegetables," and I say, "You have to eat
vegetables or you'll hurt
yourself," and I say, "
Okay, I do a lot of things that
hurt me," but she says, "
Look, you're hurting other people.
This probably isn't yours anymore. That
body belongs to someone else." And I say, "
Oh, this isn't right," and I say, "It's not mine. It's like
borrowing something. It's like asking to borrow
someone's car and crashing it, right?"
Wait, he didn't do it; someone else did,
and the car is still in the shop
after two months, I
think. So you don't want to hurt
other people's things.
This means things
that can hurt your body: a lot of risk,
not getting enough sleep, being very, very
busy. Being very, very, very busy isn't a
very
good thing. It means protecting your body.
You have to take very
good care of yourself because you have to live a long
life, and it takes so many millions of years for us to get
here, and it takes millions
of years for us to be in this
room. You have to take care of that
person. That person is very valuable. I don't care
if you think you're valuable or not.
If you are, you're one in ten.  Millions, and you
must think you're a normal person,
but if you're in this
room, millions of years of
hard work passed for you to be here, so don't
waste it. You have to have this
responsibility to sleep well, to eat
well, not to work too much,
okay? Play some rock and roll songs once in a
while. People say, "How do you play rock and
roll?" And I say, "Yeah, rock and roll." And you have to
relax, too. You have to have fun. Having fun
is one of the things
people say. You said, "No, you didn't have
time to see me, but you're
playing rock and roll for me." It's like, "I
have to have some fun, or else I can't
do
anything." It means
purity. Don't let your body hurt
other
people. And what it means is,
uh, keep spraying Sprite on your
white sneakers. You already gave these
white sneakers away. So if they get
dirty, you have to spray them
again to keep them white. This is your
body, and this is your time. You have to
take care of your time and your body. If you hurt this,
if you do something to hurt yourself,
when you get to my age, you have to go to
Doctors all the time, and I don't like it, and I
never have in my entire life. No, I haven't had
a doctor in years. And when you reach a
certain age, you have to take care of yourself. You have to
find good doctors, and you have to
keep your appointments with your doctors
and this kind of
thing. Let them open you up when
they want because you have to try to
live as long as you can. You have to
be ready to give it away. You have to take
good care of it. Don't let it get
contaminated for the next person.
Keep it pure. Keep your heart pure and
your body pure for the next person
who's going to
use it. Then it talks
about
taking care of your body. You
also have this
responsibility. This is getting
very serious. It's like, I
have problems taking care of the body I was
born with. Now you want me to take care of
my body that I haven't been born into yet?
And the answer is yes, you have a
responsibility with your
future body too. Your future body is
already blessed; it's already in
storage,
and you have a
responsibility to collect the karma
that will give you a good body in the
next life because you already
sold that one too. You already gave that one away.
So you don't just have to take care of
the body you already have.  You were born because
your future body is no longer yours; you've already
committed it. It hasn't been
given to you yet, but you already have one of the
seeds to create a good body in the
next life. It's a very fun game, it
seems to me.
Okay, I'm going to try to be
generous because
I promised my next life's body
too, and I want to have a lot of money. So, I'm
going to take care of people who are
hungry and live on the streets or people
who are in war because I want
my next body to be an amazing one
because I already promised it. It's like when
you promise your grandchild a present and you
promise them an amazing
birthday present next year, and then
you have to start collecting the
money for that
present. It depends on how much you spend,
so here it says you must be ready
to
give. Protect your body and keep it
healthy, also your future body. And it
mentions
eight things about your future body that
you must prepare now, eight
qualities of your future body that
you have to start preparing now.
You have to deliver a good body in
your next life, which means what you can
do now: collect the seeds to
make sure you have a good body in
the next
life. And by the way, it's very fun to
think about it this way.  It's so amazing
that it's not like selfish, it's not like you
have to take care of your body, you have to
make sure you have a lot of money in
the future. To me, that's
boring. No, I don't do it that way. I don't like to
do it that way. But if it tells you that you have to take
care of your next body because you're going to
give it away, you're going to hand it over, and you can't
give away cheap things, you have to give
quality things, if you put it that way, then I get
excited about my next
life's body. It's like, "Tell me what to
do then." It's
not in
the database,
and the writer of the book says, "Beb, and
find it in Shantia." I think he knew we were going to have to
find it there, so I went and found it
in the
database. And here are the eight. It's not in the database.
Help sick people in
this life so that your future body
has a long life. The first one
is to collect the
causes that your
future body—what do you call it?—when you buy a
new car that has low
mileage, you don't want to buy a car
that's going to break down.
You want a car with low
mileage for the next life.
So collect the causes to have
a long life.  The next life. And this is about
helping people who are sick.
Number
one, number two, be
patient, don't get angry.
And here you say that this has to do
with my next
life. We want it to be
attractive, we want that body to be
attractive. It's not
selfish. It's that
if you look good, more people will
approach you and come to your class,
etc. It's serious. And this is something very
old from Buddhism, and Atia says, "I am
very happy that I was born handsome because everyone
comes to my class." And it says, "It is
karma that you must prepare for your next
body." And this means, don't get angry. Don't get angry
in this life. You're
really going to tell me, "You're
making me angry," but I'm not going to get angry
because I have to teach in my next
life. You must think like this: "You
deserve for me to be angry with you, you deserve for me to be angry with you,"
but I'm
not going to
do it because I've already committed the next
body, and I have to make sure that it's
very handsome and very beautiful. It
means be
generous so that in your next life
you can be born in a country that has
money, you can be in a country that
has money, and this helps a lot.  It helps a
lot. If you're born in a
super country, you don't have the resources to
help other people, and I'm not
saying you're a bad person, you're
fine, it's very good,
like the person who built the
roads
here and also built the
student center. That's a good
Renaissance. They need roads.
Okay. Someone needs a road, a car
for the new road, and they bought cars. Okay.
Yes, we're buying.  Or cars for
everyone, and I remember
when we did this collection, like, $
000, it was a huge thing, and he said, "Okay,
I promised
this," and I went back and said, "We've already used so much
and we still don't have a floor," and he said, "Okay,
here's another $200," and it went up five times. That's why it's
so
beautiful, but be generous.
You should prepare a good body
for the next life. Live in a
country where there's money so
you can help more people. You're a
bad person if you don't have money. No, I didn't say that.
You should stop your retirements and
try to go make more money so you
can give more money. No,
I'm not saying that either. Give what you
can; it's the same as
sharing what you can. And you can
share $10, and you'll have the same
result as this person who built
the school for students. If you give what you
can, all you can, without
hurting yourself or your
family, then you should feel
comfortable having a good house, food, a
car, and share from there on, all you
can. This is all very good. It
means share power, any kind
of power you have, share it. If you're the
head of Diamond
M or if you're the head of advertising
Blah blah blah,
share your power with other people.
Share it, be generous with your
power. Let other
people share the responsibilities
if they want. Give them a
chance to do fun things.
Give them a chance to be the boss. You
are a boss. The best way to be a
boss is to let other people
share the things that belong to the boss, and
then you will be a boss. So
share the authority, share the
position you have. Don't
be
selfish or envious, and in the next life you
will be able to have power and you will be able to
share and help many
people. Keep your
promises. Keep your promises. When you
fulfill them, keep your promises. Don't
forget your promises. I think keeping your promises
is 50% remembering your
promises. So when you promise
something, try to keep a mental record
of, "Ah, okay, I promised this, so I have to do it."
Keep a mental record or
on your phone, a list of things you
promised,
and keep your
word. Keep your promises and don't
promise easily, but when you
promise,
fulfill it no matter what. You must
fulfill it. And then in your next
life, people will always  They'll believe you and
people will listen to you. It's so nice to
collect the
karma of people saying, "Okay, Gela,
I'm on it." It took me a long
time to find that energy, and it took me a
long time to collect it, but I
must say it's very
fun. Yesterday they were saying to me, "Like you said to
do this, so I have to do it,"
and for me it was like, "So
keep your
word, number one, be
true. You want to have a good
reputation in your next life," and this
means: Try to take care, uh,
don't talk about other
people's problems. Don't waste your time
talking to other people about other
people. Everyone, all
people, we have problems. We all have
bad habits.
If someone is in this world and they're
pretending they don't have a bad habit, they're just pretending they do
n't have a
bad habit
because you can't come into this world
unless you have bad
habits. So if someone in this world
says, "I'm as pure as snow,"
I tell them, "No, you're not," and I say, "No."
And
if you're here, this is where they put the
bad guys. This is the final part of
the class. We're the
last ones. We're all the same. We all
have the same
problems. So don't waste your time
doing  Lists in your mind of
other people's bad habits—you
have plenty to
work on, no extra. And if you
work on your own bad habits, you're
preparing a good body
for the next life, and that body will
have authority and
fame, and you can use the fame. Or you can misuse it; you
can be addicted to
fame, you can
hurt yourself trying to be famous. But
if you are famous, you can use it
if you know how to use it. It's very
helpful. Number that
we're going to see:
every country has its own
social levels, and every country is
different. You know there are
countries in the universe, not in this
world, but if your left ear is
bigger than your right, you're from high
society. It's like, "Oh look, she's very beautiful."
Why is her left ear twice as
big as her right? They laugh. But there are
worlds like that; there are worlds like that. We
have our own
weird things, or your nose is very short or very
long; you must be a good
person. Ah, there's
this question where in your
next life you might be born into the world of those with
big left ears,
or whatever is popular on that
planet. So you have to be ready.
I have a vision of my next life.  I
designed it and
observed it, and I have a persona that I know I'm going to create
in the next life,
and it must be a person who is
respected in their society. That's what I'm
trying to say, and every society is
different. In some societies, if
you talk a lot, you are respected; in other
societies, if you don't talk, you are respected.
So it doesn't
matter; every country has different
customs, but try to build and
have your karma for the next
life, so they say, "Ah, he's so handsome! His
left ear is so
big!" Try to have the
karma. And lastly,
generating
karma to have a healthy body—
we say, "Long life," that's number one,
but number one is that that body, with a
lot of vitality, must be
healthy. You can live a long life
but not a healthy one. So a long
life isn't enough. You want a
body that you can carry, that can
push you, that is healthy, that you can get
up
early, that you can build stupas and
temples, and then you can go study
for eight hours, and you are a body that has
energy,
okay, 100 times over. And then everyone pays
attention. What is the name for generating
karma for these things,
or what is it called?  Create karma
for these 0
points. Raise your hand.
Joyful effort.
The person holding the box decides
who gets the
money. I don't take it. It
's easy.
If I have three or four bad answers,
I cancel. The bet. Someone
can try one
more time. Quit. Forget it.
Show the picture. The
last paint. Paint your shoes
white. Don't forget the
picture. The picture is: Take care of your body in
this
life and take care of your body in the
next life. Take care of these
shoes. Be one of those silly people
who spray their shoes every
day because they're not your shoes anymore. They
belong to other people. You have to
take care of the body you were born with and you
have to take care of the body you do
n't have yet. It's your responsibility. Okay? I don't
know, life just got so complicated.
I
like it, and it's hard for me to take care of
myself, but if you tell me I have to take
care of myself for other people, then yes, I
answer. My boss used to take me to the
corporate office in New York, and he would
call me and say, "We have a very
big order. We have to send 10,000 rings
tomorrow to JC Pen. You have to work longer. You ca
n't go home with me."  Your
Lama and taking your class, you have to
stay here with me, and I would say, "I'm
leaving now," and he would say, "I'm going to say goodbye," and I would say, "Say goodbye to me." "Okay, I'm
not going to miss my class," and he would get angry
and say, "Okay, go."
And like months later, he would say, "
Mike, they
always call you at 4:59, right? One
minute before the company closes," and he would say, "
Come to my office," and he would say, "
Mike, you're the
only one. Without you, we're
nothing. We can't do anything. When you're
here, we know what to do, and when you're not here,
we fall apart. Everything collapses. You have to
help us. We have a huge delivery
tomorrow, please. You're the best." And I would say, "
If you tell me it's for someone else,
then I answer, 'I can do that. I'll eat
my vegetables.' If it's for
students, it's for my students.
Yesterday we had delicious enchiladas from
a group here in Mexico, and someone
tried to sneak in some
spinach,
and my cat only eats
wet food and leaves the dry food, and I
ate them all,
but if you tell me, 'Please, for others,
you have to eat your spinach.'"
So I say, "Okay, perfect, I'm on it,"
and I think, "That's how it is. If it's for
someone else, you can
do it." What time do I finish? 15
minutes. I have to stop before then because they
have to... they're
going to make me
stay. When do the
thank yous start? Okay, let's say 5
more minutes. We'll finish this point because they're going to
the next perfection. Let's finish
this perfection. First perfection. Here it
says the same thing. It applies to your possessions.
The first one is for your body. You have to
take care of your body for
others, your body of the future, for others. And
now you have to take care of your possessions,
like your car. That's a very
interesting idea. You have to take very good care of
your car because it's not yours anymore. You're
borrowing it. When you drive your
car, you're driving a car that you've already given
to someone else. Only they haven't
taken it. It's not your car. So,
you have to take very good care of your things. I don't
like taking care of
things. I don't like taking care of
things. It
bothers me to take the car for
maintenance. I hate it. I never do it.
But if you make me feel
guilty, you tell me, "We can't do it without
you, Mike. You're the special person." And
then I say, "Of course, you're right.
Someone has to take care of that car." Why?
Because maybe you have...  Taking
someone else to the hospital or something... You have
a
responsibility to take care of your things
because maybe you'll need them to help
other people. Because it's not yours anymore,
okay? You have to take care of your house. By the
way, keep your house clean of
junk
because when you die, someone has to
clean it up, and it's very irritating. Your friend
dies, and you go to their house and say, "Oh, those were
days of work here." Keep your house
clean. Don't collect too much
stuff. Keep your house clean. Keep your
life light.
Pretend you're going to die
tomorrow and don't let other people have to
clean your things. Get rid of
all that junk. By the way,
I take everything out, throw it
in the trash, and then go to bed at
10:00 at night. At 10:30, I get
up and go back for half of what I
took out, and I take it back. And maybe I
say, "Maybe you do need these shoes,"
and my wife says, "You haven't worn those
shoes in six years," and I say, "But you
never
know." So get rid of
extra stuff. Don't make someone else
clean your things. You don't know when you're going to
die. So clean it up already.  Make sure your
house is clean, like a
temple.
Okay, it's the same steps. You must be
ready to give away your
possessions. Try to increase your
generosity in your mind with your
meditations. Protect your possessions; what is
yours might be needed by someone else
next week. There's a
joke that says your clothes will go
looking for a new person when you
die. In America, they give them to
clothing stores. So, take good care of your
things. And this says: make sure you
get your things honestly. Don't
get your possessions. Your possessions
must be
clean; they must have
clean karma because you can't give them to other
people. Possessions that aren't
clean are an
interesting idea. Don't deceive people
to get things because when you die
and those things are offered to other
people, they will
be contaminated. Don't pass
contaminated things on to other people.
Everything you have must be clean;
you obtained it in clean and kind ways.
Nothing you have should have been
obtained by stealing or
deceiving. That's not appropriate.
So, we should teach this to
cleanse the karma, because
everything should be
clean. We should do this program; it
would be very
interesting. And don't
forget to gather many cool things
for your next life. So, in this life, the
motivation is that in the next
life I'm going to have amazing things
to give to other
people. Finally, I'm going to be able to have a
Tesla in my next life, and I'm going to have
something cool to give to other
people. Okay,
lastly, here we do the... and then
we do the 9,000
thanks. So here it said
body, and then it said possessions,
and it says you have to do the
same steps with your good
seeds. Very interesting, very...
[Music]
interesting. Every time you meditate, at the
end of the meditation,
practice giving away your good seeds,
like we did today. With this light,
like the sun, we can give away our good seeds,
pretend that you are
giving them away. You can teach other
people to make their own
good seeds and give away their good
seeds. So, it
says...
100. Who
said... Let's see, here are two answers.
It's a bet of $ and the other is...
and the other is one that I'm not going to
bet on, but the answer was so good
that I had to give
$. So what?  Does anger have anything to do
with this?
Raise your hand. What does anger have to do
with the exact topic we've been
talking about?
Anger destroys all your good
seeds. So there are no more good
seeds to dedicate in your next
life. Your good seeds don't even
belong to you anymore. Oh God,
seriously, I don't care about giving away my car,
but my
good seeds...
You promised to give away everything you have,
including your good seeds. Your good
seeds in your own mind don't
belong to you, nor do they belong to
other people. You have a
moral responsibility not to harm the
good seeds in your own
mind. What's the best way to destroy
the seeds, the good seeds?
Anger. And like a body, you have to avoid
anger because those
seeds you're going to destroy no longer
belong to you. It's like smashing
someone else's car; it's not yours anymore. You no longer have the
right to be
angry because you don't have the right to
destroy the good seeds in your
own mind because you already gave them away.
Wow, this is getting difficult. I'm
almost done, and here it
says one last
thing: it's also your
moral responsibility not only to protect the good
seeds you have but to
multiply them. It's your
moral responsibility if you're saving money for
someone who already...  Alui, you've
given it to them, it's your
responsibility to invest it, earn
interest, and give them more
money. Do
you understand? I'm saving $0 for the
Latin American Tour,
and in the bathroom, my friends and I decided I have to
give it today,
but I should try to earn some
interest before giving it to them, right? Alui, I
should give them $11,
or is it your
moral responsibility to give more than you committed to?
Then you have to earn interest on
your good seeds now, $100. And now I'm going to be
quiet and sit down and
listen to the
thank yous. We have to do this,
right?
Last
thing, how are you going to earn interest on your
mental seeds? You have to raise your hand. The
money comes out of the orange box.
You have to use the
microphone. By the
way, for the next withdrawal, when you
come, try to be the person who
holds the
microphone, and that way you can make a deal
for
50%.
Okay, bring a
fake box. I'm going to give two. And the answer is
correct. Within my mind and my
body, everything. I'm going to repeat: I have
mental impressions in my mind. I have
good
seeds. They are no longer mine. Everything else I
have, I've already dedicated to other
people. I'm just
saving them.  I can deliver them with
interest instead of giving 00 for the Tour.
I can give 11,000 if I invest it
wisely. How do I do it? How do I
easily convert 100 seeds into 110?
Coffee meditation delivers more seeds than you
promised. OK, it's always good. By the
way, people ask me for business advice. They
lend you money for a business, they give you 100,
you promise 110. And if you can, give 120 and you'll
be very
popular and people will lend you
money like crazy. Always give them more
money than you promised, also with
your own
mental seeds. Okay, we're ready for